# Sire Nathanæl Xiæ Yeuoaiaouey

**Actively Looking** 

nathaniel.brown.cavazzi@gmail.com

# Summary

Linkedin Profile URL: http://linkedin.com/in/sirenathanael ----- Personable creative self starter that has a strong background in all forms of technology with extensive experience in customer service, sales, software development, photography, graphic design, accounting, and project management. - Architected and developed multiple large scale software projects for interactive web applications and online storefronts - Automated systems and deployment infrastructure with Chef (by OpsCode) for 1,000,000 MAU FaceBook application and mobile environments. In addition, I have deployed Chef to manage the linux environments of every software environment I have worked on since 2009. - Mastered Adobe SiteCatalyst and Kontagent for enterprise Analytics implementations (Jenny Craig, Slotspot Mobile, Video Licensing, Multi-variate A/B/\* testing) - Managed teams as large as 20 software developers working on multiple project initiatives with multi-million dollar budgets - Produced two unique technology conferences, over 450 attendees combined - Extensive experience handling a variety of different organizations through various levels of communication - Presented on multiple occasions in workshops and seminars internationally - Reduced burn-rates drastically within multiple corporations while increasing quality and experience of talent and technical infrastructure - Interviewed hundreds of technical candidates and screened thousands of resumes Specialties: Frontend & Backend Developer, B2B / B2C Sales, Public Speaker, Business Development, Marketing, Event Production, Information Architect, Project Manager

# Experience

## Emperor at Vidli Video Distribution

April 2009 - Present (6 years 2 months)

Handling all management duties relating to architecture, user interface design, wireframing, front-end and backend development, art direction, branding, social media, landing pages, advanced metrics, SEO, Google adSense, graphic design for the website as well as print brochures, technical representation for VC and Angel investment. Hands on with Ruby on Rails, AJAX, CSS/XHTML, Information Architecture, UX, graphic design, and technical architecture. - Created the business objectives and key revenue streams - Led a team that included Flash/AS3, Ruby on Rails, user experience, graphic design, sales, and affiliate marketing members

#### Owner, Photographer, Videographer at Pærity

September 2005 - Present (9 years 9 months)

Collaborating with Models, Make Up Artists, Stylists, Clothing Designers, and Graphic Artists to produce still photography for websites, print campaigns, and portfolios. - Professional Lighting Expert for Film -

Location Scout for Film and Movie Productions in British Columbia - Artist Photographer for Headshots for Marketing / Self Promotion - Network of ~40,000 on various industry specific social networks - Event photographer for BC Fashion Week, Vancouver Fashion Week, Miss Pole Dance Canada

#### **International Speaker and Instructor at Freelance Eductator**

September 2005 - Present (9 years 9 months)

Distributed Cluster Management with Chef - October 6th, 2009 http://vimeo.com/10884991 Using Chef, the new all Ruby server infrastructure management system, guiding through setting up a distributed network architecture in an automated fashion. Leveraging chef on the cloud with Ubuntu, RHEL, and CentOS in a multi network environment spanning from Amazon's EC2, 1&1, Rackspace, and Slicehost. Learning not only the fundamental concepts of Chef, but how to practically use it to automate your network infrastructure with installations, version upgrades, centralized user management, as well as deployment strategies to remove complications of managing as well as scaling clusters of servers in the wild. --- AJAX and Ruby on Rails JavaScript Templates (RJS) ~ December 6th, 2006 With Rail's integrated JavaScript templating language called RJS, providing dynamic JavaScript with ease with the use of Ruby. No longer do you have to use XML to have the AJAX functionality you crave. By using the RJS templates within the last major release of Ruby on Rails, you are able to directly use server-side variables such as data stored in sessions, to write your JavaScript and update elements on the fly. --- Getting Started with Ruby and Rails ~ September 8th, 2006 & July 26th, 2006 Beginning with Ruby, then onto the framework of Ruby on Rails. This course will get you started with Rails from the least common denominator, but will give even 99.9% of the experienced Rails developers one of the most profound undiscovered secrets. This course will be a start to finish run down of all the corners of the Rails world, and leave you the knowledge of where you can explore deeper. --- CSS Layouts at Vancouver Web 2.0 Forum ~ September 27th, 2005 With the advent of CSS based templates becoming more and more a requirement for deployment, changing the mindset from a table centric paradigm to a more open and flexible CSS based layout can be a somewhat daunting task.

#### **Eternal Disciple at Shoalin**

January 2004 - Present (11 years 5 months)

Qigong, Kung Fu, Tai Chi

#### **Emperor at Purefame Artist Network**

January 2000 - Present (15 years 5 months)

The central location to find out about all artists in the galaxy. Whether it be a painter, a musician, a photographer, a video enthusiast, voice over specialist, an athlete, or a common poet, Purefame is a source for crætive inspiration and artistic crætion.

#### Technical Architect at Self-employed

September 1997 - Present (17 years 9 months)

- DevOps (Chef, Ubuntu/RHEL, MySQL/Cassandra/PostgreSQL, AWS) - Ruby 1.8.x to 1.9.x & Rails 0.x to 4.x & PHP 3.x to 4.x Development - JavaScript / AJAX / jQuery / EXTJS - Appcelerator Titanium Mobile

Development (iPhone and Android) - CSS 2 & 3 Development (SASS > SCSS) - HTML5 - UX / User Experience Specialist - Logo / Brand Design / Brand Awareness - Social Media Expert - Google Advertising Expert - Facebook Advertising Expert with Targeted Analysis through Adobe - Metrics (Clicky, Adobe SiteCatalyst, Kontagent, Google Analytics) - GIT (GitHub/BitBucket), SVN, CVS - Web Hosting (Custom Enterprise w/ Disaster Recovery, Cloud), Domain Registration, DNS - Technical Training for Junior or Senior Development Teams - Project Management - Graphic Design (Photoshop Expert & Adobe CS4 Master)

## Weddingful - Social Wedding Community at VP of Technology (Remote and some onsite)

May 2013 - February 2014 (10 months)

\* Working with the Cheif Executive Officer, Cheif Operations Officer, and managing the entire tech team to design, implement, test, and maintain features on the website (Ruby on Rails, jQuery, BackboneJS, SASS/SCSS, MySQL, CoffeeScript) \* Writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code that is entirely bug free \* Providing support and troubleshooting production issues as needed \* Automating the systems infrastructure with Amazon Web Services (EC2 and CloudFront) \* Managing site growth and scaling the infrastructure as the site grows in traffic and use \* Learning cutting-edge technical knowledge and applying useful concepts to solve real-world problems

#### Senior Development Lead (SDL) at Atimi Software

January 2013 - March 2013 (3 months)

\* NHL and NBA sports framework development for mobile environment (iPhone, BlackBerry, Android) \* PHP, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Highly Custom JavaScript for secure cross domain access protocol

#### DevOps Lead / Data Scientist at Blitzoo Interactive

February 2012 - June 2012 (5 months)

While working at Blitzoo, I managed the continuous integration system with Jenkins. In addition to managing the Chef systems automation repository building new features and support for the various infrastructure requirements for over 50 servers in the AWS EC2 cloud and local XEN instances. In addition to managing the infrastructure for over a million active players on the Virtual Slot and Card Casino called SlotSpot, I also helped lead the implementation of the mobile analytics system to track usage and profits.

#### Owner, CEO & President at Inimit Innovations Inc.

January 2003 - November 2008 (5 years 11 months)

Contracted with many organizations performing duties such as front-end development (AJAX/CSS/XHTML), Ruby on Rails programming, managed hosting, custom enterprise hosting, website design and architecture, creating database architectures and data modeling, user interface design, SEO, and graphic design. With on-site and remote contracts ranging from 6 months to 18+ months in length. Provided customer advice and consultations, involving contract negotiation and timelines for software development projects as well as hiring. - Managed project plans and technical architectures for a wide range of software for business automation and optimization. Performed duties as the chief engineer on eCommerce, Content

Management, Digital Asset Management Systems, as well as customized per project architectures. - Clients included Jenny Craig, EA Sports, Novartis, Clariant, Intersport - Project managed teams as large as 20 developers - Technical and IT strategy management to company executives - Designed and conveyed technical specifications to developers - Recruit, interview, and manage developers while identifying role requirements, writing job postings, as well as training - Facilitated developer meetings to discuss timelines and set milestones - Managed multiple application development teams (Java, AppleScript, .NET, Rails, PHP, AJAX, CSS, Designers)

#### Owner, Event Craetor / Producer at Open Source Events

January 2004 - October 2006 (2 years 10 months)

Architect of two world-renowned conferences with attendances in excess of 300 participants over multiple days of presentations & workshops. Events featured international speakers. - Pioneered the first ever Ruby on Rails conference in the world - Sold out Canada on Rails conference with 300+ attendees - Organized speakers to give presentations such as Rasmus Lerdorf (Creator of PHP), David Hansson (Creator of Ruby on Rails), and Bruce Perens (Open Source advocate) - Designed and developed website and branding (CMS, eCommerce ticketing, Newsletter) - Organizing corporate and media sponsorship from leading organizations - Locating venues including negotiating and securing contracts - Project Management of volunteers and organizers

#### Head of Technology, Management Consultant at Onison Corporation

January 2003 - June 2004 (1 year 6 months)

International software solution provider to international organizations. Documented R&D being performed by the entire organization which was required for government grants (such as SR&ED), providing technical leadership for the production of proprietary software while leveraging open source technology, advising and leading new approaches for features across the application suite, in addition to guiding the growth of our team as a technical expert during interviews and board meetings.

#### Partner, Director of eCommerce at Backbone Technology

June 2001 - March 2003 (1 year 10 months)

Responsible for all facets of the eCommerce deployments as well as leading new features for the Expression CMS. Through the use of the CMS & eCommerce application, clients were given the ability to maintain their website presence with ease through a secure web administration panel which could be accessed from any internet connection globally.

#### MyCityRadio at Director of Information Technology

September 2000 - February 2001 (6 months)

MyCityRadio was a leading edge streaming media company providing a range of video stations online. There were three full time broadcasts daily running from 8am to 8pm.

## Education

## Cariboo Hill Secondary

High School, Sciences, 1996 - 2000

Grade: 12

# Skills & Expertise

**SQL** 

**Software Development** 

Java

**JavaScript** 

Microsoft SQL Server

**XML** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

**HTML** 

**C**#

Linux

MySQL, Photoshop, Graphic Design, JavaScript,

Chef, Metrics, CoffeeScript, AB Te

**MySQL** 

**Graphic Design** 

Chef

**Metrics** 

**AB Testing** 

**Analytics** 

**HAML** 

**ExtJS** 

**Prototype** 

**JIRA** 

**OmniGraffle** 

**AWS** 

Linux server

**Subversion** 

**Omniture SiteCatalyst** 

Adsense

**Database Design** 

EC2

**Software Project Management** 

**Landing Pages** 

Capistrano

Ubuntu

**CentOS** 

RHEL

**FreeBSD** 

**Performance Metrics** 

**KPI** 

**Nagios** 

Ganglia

**Jenkins** 

**SASS** 

Facebook Ads

**Fashion Photography** 

**Studio Lighting** 

**Event Management** 

**International Event Management** 

**BSD** 

**IPFW** 

**Martial Artist Expert** 

# Languages

English, Old (ca.450-1100)

English, Middle (1100-1500)

**English** 

French

French, Middle (ca.1400-1600)

French, Old (842-ca.1400)

**Spanish** 

Italian

Latin

# Sire Nathanæl Xiæ Yeuoaiaouey

Actively Looking

nathaniel.brown.cavazzi@gmail.com



Contact Sire Nathanæl on LinkedIn